

IFTEKHER MAHMUD

Mailing Address

Gmail: iftekhermahmud1@gmail.com

Address: Shyamoli, Dhaka

Phone: 01794607199, 01580359517

Portfolio link:

iftekher-mahmud.netlify.app

Interpersonal

- Fast learning
- Highly Motivated
- Teamwork and time management
- multitasking and organizational
- effective communication and leadership
- analytical and problemsolving

Technically Skilled

- HTML
- CSS
- SCSS
- Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- React
- PHP
- MySQL
- iQuery
- WordPress
- Laravel

Career Objective

To advance my career by securing a challenging position in a progressive organization that values growth and innovation. With 2+ years of experience, I am eager to apply my skills and knowledge to make meaningful contributions, achieve professional excellence, and effectively fulfill all assigned responsibilities

Work Experiences

Innovative Soft

Duration: 11 Sep 2023 - Present

Jr. Programmer

- **Designed and developed responsive user interfaces.**
- Integrated and JavaScript plugins to enhance functionality and improve.
- Implemented Laravel packages such as Laravel Socialite, Laravel Passport/sanctum, job queues and many more.
- Developed backend features using Laravel, including advanced Eloquent relationships like (one-to-many, many-to-many), data handling, form request validation, and business logic.
- Maintained and optimized existing Projects by troubleshooting, identifying, and resolving critical bugs.
- Managed Laravel-based websites, implementing custom features, improving code quality, and optimizing database queries using advanced query building and indexing.
- Designed and integrated RESTful APIs using Laravel Sanctum for token-based authentication, ensuring secure and efficient data exchange between web, mobile, and desktop platforms.
- Developed scalable and secure APIs for mobile and desktop applications using Laravel
- Developed custom middleware to handle user requests and secure routes, ensuring authorization rules and application flow.

Security Automation System

Duration: 01 Feb 2023 – 30 Aug 2023

Web Developer

- Website Development: Install Elementor, Elementor Pro, and WordPress page builders to design and build custom websites.
- * Responsive Design
- Content and Media Management: Content demo imports and efficiently set up media files. Uploaded and managed content, including posts and products
- Custom Styling and Scripting: Applied custom CSS and JavaScript to enhance website aesthetics and functionality.
- Performance Optimization: Implemented performance optimization strategies to improve site speed and efficiency.

Kushtia Polytechnic Institute

Duration: 01 Feb 2022 - 30 Aug 2023

Web Developer (Learning, Learner, Freelancer)

- Installation and Setup: Successfully installed and configured WordPress on both local development environments and web hosting servers.
- **Website Development**: Install Elementor, and WordPress page builders to design and build websites.
- * Responsive Design
- **Performance Optimization**: Implemented performance optimization strategies to improve site speed and efficiency.
- Html, CSS, JavaScript

Work With Projects

Portfolio Website

Link: https://iftekher-mahmud.netlify.app

Link: https://iftekher2108.github.io/iftekher-portfolio

Material Calculation App

Link: https://matel-calculation-next.vercel.app

Tesla Elevator

Link: https://tesla-elevator.com

Pet Consultant Website

Link: https://iftekher2108.github.io/pet-consultency-templete

SMTA Group Website

Link: https://smta-group.com

Restaurants Website

Link: https://iftekher2108.github.io/restaurent-templete

Currency Convert App

Link_1: https://iftekher2108.github.io/currency-converter Vue_Link_2: https://vue-currency-convert.netlify.app

Calculator Web App

Link: https://iftekher2108.github.io/calculator-project

Whole Sales Website

Link: https://iftekher2108.github.io/uk-whole-sale

Adora Solutions Website

Link: https://adora-solutions.com

Training Summary

Industrial Attachment:

Program : Industrial Attachment Training Program

Institute : Computer Space Institute

Department : Computer Technology Location : Kushtia, Khulna

Year : 2022 Duration : 4 months

Language Proficiency

- Bengali
- English

Educational Qualification

Diploma in Engineering:

Institute : Kushtia Polytechnic Institute

Department : Computer Technology

Passing Year : 2022

Result : 3.42 (CGPA Out of 4.00)

Board : Technical

Secondary School Certificate (S.S.C):

Institute : Bheramara Pilot Model High School

Subject : General Mechanical

Passing Year : 2018

Result : 4.82 (GPA Out of 5.00)

Personal Information

❖ Name : Iftekher Mahmud Pervez❖ Father's Name : Late. Habibur Rahman

❖ Mother's Name : Mst. Parul

❖ Date of Birth : 21 December 2002

Nationality : BangladeshMarital Status : Unmarried

Present Address : 196/3 W Agargaon, N Shyamoli Dhaka, 1207

Permanent Address : Kacharipara, Bheramara, Kushtia

❖ Religion : Islam❖ Gender : Male

Reference

Name: Md. Tanvir Ahamed: Name: Md. Robiul Islam Khan
Organization: Drik Picture Library Limited
Designation: System & Network Engineer

Name: Md. Robiul Islam Khan
Organization: Kushtia Polytechnic Institute
Designation: Chief Instructor (Computer)

Mobile : 01772-159910 Address : Kushtia Sadar, Kushtia

Relation : Professional Mobile : 01711-270796 E-mail : Tanvir.tarif@gmail.com Relation : Educational

Note: I declare that all the information include here are true and complete to the best of my knowledge.